Oh, come on, Chelsea.
Is this about money?
I'd be happy to pay the lease
on your apartment.
It's not about money, you ass.
It's ridiculous that we're engaged
and not living together.
Well, excuse me for being old-fashioned.
I'm just not comfortable with us
living in sin.
- So you think we should stop having sex?
- No, no, no.
It's not the sin I object to,
it's the living in it.
There is no reason to renew
the lease on my apartment...
...when I'm here every night.
CHARLIE:
I love having you here. I thought...
You gonna eat your pickle?
- I'm gonna eat my pickle.
You can crawl out whenever.
You're almost done with your sandwich
and your pickle's just sitting there.
- I like to eat it last.
This is not stupid, Charlie.
How very European of you.
Here's another pickle. Shut up.
You are so full of it.
Give me one reason
why I shouldn't be living here.
- I can give you several.
- This ought to be good.
Well, go ahead.
CHARLIE: You mean, right now?
Dance, monkey, dance.
Okay. Well, there's the safety issue.
Keep your apartment
for the same reason...
...that airplanes are equipped with oxygen
masks and cruise ships have life rafts.
If the Titanic had enough life rafts...
...Leonardo and Kate would've lived
happily ever after.
Oops.
You're comparing our relationship
to Titanic?
Rope-a-dope, rope-a-dope.
CHARLIE:
No, no, no. Of course not.
P.S., that was a very romantic movie.
Thanks for making me watch it again.
He's still swinging. The kid's got heart.
CHARLIE: Where are you going?
Home.
See? You just proved my point.
Where would you go right now
if you didn't have your own apartment?
Suppose you all enjoyed listening to that.
- Huh?
- Beg pardon?
I enjoyed it.
Can't sleep, huh?
No.
This Chelsea-moving-in thing
is really bugging me.
Why are you up?
I realized you were drinking yourself
into a miserable stupor...
...over this whole situation...
...and I just want to be a part of that.
Thanks.
I hate to say it,
but I think Chelsea might be right.
You don't hate to say it.
Oh, did I say, "I hate to say it?"
I meant, I can't wait to say it.
But I did admire how you ferociously
defended an unwinnable position...
...by comparing your relationship
to the Titanic.
That was beautiful.
Oh, come on, who remembers
the names of boats that don't sink?
Sure, sure. I couldn't give you a zeppelin
other than the Hindenburg.
Still, it was not your finest moment.
There was a time it would've worked.
Yeah, back when you were dating
silicone simpletons.
Unfortunately,
Chelsea's too smart for your crap.
Yeah, and there's not an ounce
of silicone in those babies.
Shoot, I owe Berta 5 bucks.
But more to the point,
why are you so afraid to have her move in?
Not afraid of her moving in, that's easy.
Moving her out's the bitch.
So you're already assuming
you're gonna break up?
Oh, come on, what evidence is there
to suggest that it'll end any other way?
Well, I think she's capable
of a long-term commitment.
And you, you could change.
- You don't believe that.
- No. I was just trying to be supportive.
- You're not doing a very good job.
- I'm not trying very hard.
Let me ask you a question.
What did you think was gonna happen
when you and Chelsea got married?
Honestly, I never thought that far ahead.
I figured we could stretch
the engagement out...
...for a couple of years and by then,
who knows?
Maybe I'd die, maybe she'd get fat.
Well, kudos to you for not bringing that up
in the argument.
Wasn't easy.
You know what you have to do,
don't you?
I don't have to do anything, Alan.
If not living together is a deal breaker, then
she's free to break off the engagement...
...and go on her merry way.
She most certainly is.
So you know what you have to do.
Yes, I know what I have to do.
- Are you done torturing me?
- Almost.
I'm the king of the world!
Okay, now I'm done.
Here.
What's this?
Alan's house key.
Why?
Because I want you to move in,
and I didn't have time to make a new one.
Plus, he kind of pissed me off last night.
You want me to move in?
Yes.
I thought about it and you were right.
Uh-huh.
Which is not to say I was wrong, but, uh...
Okay, I was wrong.
You're sure you want me to move in?
Absolutely not.
But I figure, what the hell? I mean,
it's gonna happen sooner or later, right?
Oh, shut up.
Come on in, I'll make some coffee.
What's all this?
Let's just say I had faith in you.
Oh.
Oh...
Eww.
Those go upstairs in the master bedroom.
Careful, they're fragile.
Okay, you and me need to talk.
I know, I know.
You didn't sign up for this.
You work for me, not her.
And it's bad enough you have to put up
with Zippy and the chimp.
No. I like her better than you.
So from now on, I'm working for her.
- What?
- You need something, you ask her.
She talks to me, we decide.
- I don't get a vote?
- Yeah, you get a vote.
One vote out of three.
Good luck with that.
Oh, boy.
You like it?
Don't the colors just liven the place up?
Well...
Uh...
Oh, boy.
Come on, I wanna show you
what I did in the bathroom.
Oh, boy.
What do you think?
I don't know.
I have this sudden urge
to pee sitting down.
You like the new towels?
I guess.
- What was wrong with the old ones?
- They didn't match my shower curtain.
- What was wrong with my shower curtain?
- It didn't match your towels.
Maybe that's how I tell them apart.
Oh. Oh, please, tell me that's one
of those Zen sand gardens.
You know very well
that's Sir Lancelot's litter box.
- You brought the cat?
- Of course I brought the cat.
- What did you think I was gonna do?
- I don't know.
Return him to the wild?
You're being ridiculous.
Is it ridiculous to want the turds
in my bathroom to be human?
Fine, we'll put it in the laundry room.
Near my clean clothes? Forget it.
So where am I supposed to put it?
Oh, I don't think you really want me
to tell you where to put it.
CHARLIE:
I'm just saying it's too much.
Pillows, towels, shower curtains,
cat crap.
I don't like it. I don't need it.
I don't want it.
What do you want me to do?
You want me to leave?
CHARLIE:
No, no. No. You just got here. I'll leave.
It'll make more room for you
and Sir Crapsalot.
Charlie.
- Get a good earful?
- No.
I did. And I don't appreciate
being called Sir Crapsalot.
Good. For some reason,
I can't find my house key.
I hope you're happy with yourself.
Why would I start now?
Hey.
- How'd you find me?
- Wasn't hard.
When you're not volunteering to read stories
or feed the homeless, you're usually here.
Bay Breeze, extra pineapple.
I'm not cut out
for this living-together stuff, Alan.
- I mean, I tried, I really tried.
- That's true.
You gave it a whole hour
and 20 minutes.
Hey, now Berta owes me 5 bucks.
Charlie, it's not really that difficult
to live with a woman.
Says the man
who's been thrown out twice.
I didn't say it wasn't hard for them.
Did you see the salt-and-pepper shakers
Chelsea put in the kitchen?
No.
They're like these foot-high
ceramic roosters...
...with little S and P holes in their beaks.
Oh, cute. I think I saw those
in the Williams-Sonoma catalog.
What am I freaking out about? A woman's
been living with me for six years.
Cheap shot. Oh.
Canned pineapple?
It's not just the salt shakers.
It's the fancy pillows on the bed,
the fruity towels in the bathroom.
And then there's the clothes
and the shoes. Oh, my God, the shoes.
She's got almost as many as I do.
And lest we forget, she brought her big,
fat, pooping cat to live with us.
As opposed to what,
having it put to sleep?
I suggested letting it go.
I didn't even think of that.
The cat aside, you do know it was wrong
to storm out the way you did.
Of course I know.
I'm an ass, not an idiot.
One does not preclude the other.
You realize this has nothing to do
with the cat or the towels...
...or the pillows, don't you?
Tell you what.
Here's 20 bucks.
Don't tell me what it's really about.
Boy, you're putting me
in a tough spot here, Charlie.
- Forty.
- Goodnight.
Nah. I care too much about you two kids.
Here.
Now, the reason you panicked
is that you real-
This is just 20.
Is it? Oh.
My mistake.
The reason you panicked and ran away...
...is that you recognize
that the old Charlie is dying.
But what you have to understand is he has
to die in order for a new Charlie to be born.
That makes sense.
- Let me ask you a question.
- Of course.
Does the new Charlie
still have the old brother?
Absolutely. And he's here for you.
Man, I can't catch a break.
So how pissed off was Chelsea
when I left?
It was pretty bad at first.
Did you really suggest that she do
something impossible...
...with the kitty-litter box?
I didn't suggest anything.
She may have inferred.
I think I may have been able
to smooth it over for you a little bit.
Really? What did you say?
I said you had the maturity of a 9-year-old
and that she had to make allowances.
That's good.
That's good, make it her fault.
So now all you have to do is go home,
admit that you're a frightened little man...
...who doesn't deserve her love,
and beg for her forgiveness.
Groveling comes easy for you,
doesn't it?
Not at first. I didn't really hit my stride
till my second marriage.
Oh, by the way,
have you seen my house key anywhere?
CHARLIE:
Nope.
Oh, Chelsea...
...I was such a fool.
Thank God my brother talked some sense
into me.
Oh, Charlie, I love your brother.
He's so smart and masculine...
...and yet his feminine side
makes him sensitive and intuitive.
You're right.
I only tease him because I'm jealous.
And secretly gay.
Oh, hello.
Don't worry.
This ain't the most embarrassing thing
I ever walked in on you doing.
Oh, yeah. Thanks for not making
a big thing about that.
Right back at you.
You know, I really should cut down
on the talking to myself.
Yes, you should.
It's getting a little weird.
Son of a bitch.
Can I say I'm sorry again,
or are you sick of it?
Mm. Say it again. Let's see.
I'm sorry.
Nope. Still fun.
And?
And I'm a big, stupid jerk.
And I'd really like to go upstairs
and finish this apology with my mouth.
Charlie, a moment.
Not now, Alan.
Yeah, well, there's a bit of a situation,
and I'm afraid I'm gonna have to insist.
I better talk to him.
He's about to go full fruit fly.
- What is your problem?
- I noticed you put a lot of stuff in my room.
I was wondering
how long it was gonna stay there.
I've been wondering the same thing
about you.
How am I supposed to live in that room...
...if you and Chelsea
are gonna use it as a closet?
Tell you what,
I'll give you a break on the rent.
- I haven't been paying rent.
- There it is.
Fine, I'll manage somehow.
- Alan, wait.
- What?
I need you to pull your car
out of the garage.
- Why?
- You don't expect Chelsea...
- ...to park on the street, do you?
- So I have to park on the street?
You don't have to.
You can park it at your place.
- I don't have a place.
- There it is.
Leave your clicker on the coffee table.
Wait, wait, Charlie.
If I don't have a clicker and a house key...
- ...how am I supposed to get in?
- There it is.
I don't have to pee.
Damn it, I have to pee.
Ow.
Son of a bitch.
Ski poles. Ski poles.
Ow.
Oh, good, a litter box.
This is delicious.
Sure is.
Glad you like it. There's plenty more.
Jake, would you pass me the chicken?
It's fish, Dad.
Hope you're not allergic to Sir Lancelot.
I'll be fine as long as he doesn't sleep
on my face again.
He is a snuggler, isn't he?
Yeah. By the way, do you know
if anybody rented your old apartment yet?
Actually somebody just scooped it up.
- Oh.
- Why, are you thinking of moving out?
There's not a lot of room for me here.
- What's a place like that go for?
- Eighteen hundred.
On the other hand,
it's nice to be close to family.
Boy, you've got no shame at all,
do you?
I assume that's a rhetorical question.
Where's Uncle Charlie?
- Said he had some sort of meeting.
- That means poker or strip club.
I'm sure it's poker.
- used to that type of thing.
So if they show up with some
sloppy ball-handling, we'll see.
Pizza.
Hey, Gordon. Small world.
- Hey, Mr. Harper, what are you doing here?
- Oh, I just rented this place.
Decided I needed a weekend getaway.
From Malibu?
You'd be surprised.
It gets crowded sometimes.
Okay.
What happened to the woman
that used to lived here?
She lives with me in Malibu.
We're engaged.
- And you're hanging out here all alone?
- Yep.
- You know what you are, Mr. Harper?
- What?
A genius.
Thanks, Gordon. Good night.
Good night.
It's nice when someone gets you.